SHRADHA SAXENA

C-35/1, Veernagar Colony, Jagadhari Yamunanagar, Haryana-135001

Contact: 8168220586; Email: shradha.saxena11@gmail.com

<u>OBJECTIVE</u>: Seeking a challenging and rewarding opportunity in the industry which is more in line with my professional background and which effectively utilizes my excellent analytical and technical skills in the field of Human Resources.

SUMMARY

Result-focused HR Recruiter with 11+ years of experience, equipped with a diverse and promising skill-set in IT and Non- IT space, conducive to providing optimal support to internal and external stakeholders. Full cycle recruiter passionate about HR analytics, committed to client service and creative recruitment strategies. Successfully identifies and closes top industry talent

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Nextleap Advisory and Search Services Pvt. Ltd.

July 2022 - Present

Recruitment Specialist, Remote

Roles & Responsibilities

- Working on both Technical and Non Technical Requirements.
- Collaborated with hiring managers to understand job requirements and expectations.
- Responsible for end-to-end recruitment process which included sourcing, screening, scheduling interviews.
- Source qualified candidates through job portals (Naukri, LinkedIn), including but not limited to internet postings, employee referrals, database and networking
- Negotiate salary and joining duration, and submitting them to the client..
- Schedule interviews, with regular follow up with the client as well as with the candidate to make the placement in regular basis
- After interview follow up with the client regarding the feedback and keep track of the interviewed candidates, and make sure that they should join if get the offer
- Preparation and Maintenance of MIS for keeping track of candidates who have been interviewed, scheduled for interview, rejected, selected or offered on daily basis.
- Follow up of candidates at regular intervals pre and post joining.
- Tools used for sourcing: Naukri, LinkedIn, Monster posting job openings on social media.
- Clients worked: Annalect India, Ernst & Young, KPMG, IVY Technology, IQOR, Rational IT Services.

Freelance Recruiter

Sep. 2014- June 2022

Roles & Responsibilities

- Advertised and managed position listings, organising interviews with suitable candidates.
- Sourced candidates through Naukri, TimesJobs, LinkedIn and other social media platforms, validating suitability for available positions.
- Interviewed potential candidates, taking accurate notes to determine suitability for available positions.
- Managed interview process on behalf of clients and candidates, maintaining appropriate confidentiality with both parties.
- Briefed candidates about responsibilities, salary and benefits of jobs.
- Balanced client and candidate needs to achieve outstanding satisfaction ratings.
- Used candidate databases to match right person to client role requirements.
- Informed candidates about both positive or negative interview results.
- Clients worked: JK Tyres, GMR Power, Frankfinn, Safexpress, Infosys, TCS

Sobell Finance Ltd. May 2014 – Sep. 2014

HR Manager, Delhi

Roles & Responsibilities

- Analysis all requirements of the company.
- Doing Boolean searches, Google searches and searching profiles from different networking sites like linkedin, facebook, twitter etc
- Search candidates according to the client requirements and do the 1st and final level screening
- Negotiate the salary and joining duration
- Preparation and maintenance of MIS for keeping track of candidates who have been interviewed, schedule for the interview, rejected, selected or offered on daily basis.
- Prepare Offer letters, Appointment letters, Confirmation Letters, Termination Letters etc
- Conduct the various types of employee engagement activities
- Direct reporting to CMD.

Job Alert Consultant

May 2012 – June 2013

Team Lead- Recruitment, Gwalior

Roles & Responsibilities

- Managed Clients, talking to them on regular basis, taking requirements from them and understanding their requirements.
- Handled a team of 6 employees.
- Used Boolean Searches, Google Searches, and searching profiles from different networking sites like, LinkedIn, Facebook, Instagram etc
- Search candidates according to the client requirements .
- Negotiate salary and joining duration, and submitting them to the client.
- Schedule interviews, with regular follow up with the client as well as with the candidate to make the placement in regular basis.
- Preparation and Maintenance of MIS for keeping track of candidates who have been interviewed, scheduled for interview, rejected, selected or offered on daily basis.
- Follow up of candidates at regular intervals pre and post joining.
- Direct Reporting to the CEO.
- Clients worked: MindShift Interactive, Hunka Technologies, Ignitee, Hinduja Interactive.

ARC Management Consultant

Dec. 2009 -

May 2012

Team Lead- Recruitment, Gwalior

Roles & Responsibilities:

- Managed Clients, talking to them on regular basis, taking requirements from them and understanding their requirements.
- Handled a team of 4 employees.
- Managing End to End Recruitment.
- Used Boolean Searches, Google Searches, and searching profiles from different networking sites like, linkedin, facebook, twitter etc.
- Search candidates according to the client requirements .
- Negotiate salary and joining duration, and submitting them to the client.
- Schedule interviews, with regular follow up with the client as well as with the candidate to make the placement in regular basis .
- Follow up of candidates at regular intervals pre and post joining.
- Direct Reporting to the CEO.

 Clients worked: Indusind Bank, HDFC Bank, Aviva Life, Birla Sunlife, Max Life, Tata AIG, HDFC Life, Kotak Mahindra Life

KARAN CAP'S

Management Trainee HR, Gwalior 2009

July 2008 - July

Roles & Responsibilities

- Entrusted with the responsibility of managing the Recruitment Cycle ranging from Sourcing, Screening, Scheduling, Pre-employment Tests. Interviewing Applicants, Short Listing Candidates, Forwarding for Comprehensive Structured Interview.
- Conduct Interviews and Involved in Salary Negotiation, Coordinating Joining Formalities, and Conceptualize Induction Schedule.

EDUCATIONAL CREDENTIALS

DIPLOMA IN TRAINING & DEVELOPMENT, 2016

The Indian Society for Training & Development (ISTD), New Delhi

MASTERS OF BUSINESS ADMINISTRATION, HR, 2009

Jiwaji University, Gwalior

BACHELOR OF SCIENCE, BIOTECHNOLOGY, 2007

Jiwaji University, Gwalior

TECHNICAL PROFICIENCY

MS Office, Internet Application, MIS

TRAINING UNDERTAKEN

Undergone 45 days Summer Training in UFLEX LTD., Malanpur, on the Topic Employee Welfare.

PROJECT UNDERTAKEN

Major Research Project on, "EFFECT OF TRAINING ON THE JOB PERFORMANCE".

ACHIEVEMENTS

- Achieved 1st position in Speech competition.
- Won prizes and Certificates in Dance Competition.
- Achieved 1st position in Painting Competition.
- Actively Participated in Co Curricular Activities and always praised by Faculty members in College and School.

Hobbies: Painting and Internet Surfing **References:** Available on Request